Finding Aid for the James L. Clark Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
James L. Clark Papers
Undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0081
1.26 linear feet
Biographical Sketch
James Levan Clark was born February 10, 1869 in Mackville, Kentucky. He attended the Vanderbilt Biblical School from 1893 to 1894. In 1911 he was elected president of Kentucky Wesleyan College and served in that capacity until 1919. In 1916 he was awarded an honorary Doctor of Laws degree from the University of Kentucky.
Scope and Content Note
The James L. Clark Papers are composed of 1.25 linear feet of sermon typescripts, manuscripts, and writing tablets. The papers are divided into three series:
Sermons—Typescripts—typescripts of sermons Clark gave on various themes and specific biblical stories
Manuscripts—manuscripts sorted by year
Memorabilia—Clark’s writing tablets
- Sermons—Typescripts
  - Anniversary (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - “Basis of Reward for Christian Service” through “Burden Bearing” (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - “Called and Blessed” through “Choosing” (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - “The Child in the Midst” through “Christ and the Church” (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - “Christian Education Campaign” through “A Christian Day” (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - “Christ’s Prayer for his Crucifiers” through “The Church in Intercession and Preparation for Service” (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - “Lities of Refuge” through “Class and Forms of Prayer” (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - “The Communion of Saints” through “Conviction of Sin” (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - “The Corinthian Church” (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - “The Corinthian Letter” through “Counting the Cost” (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - “A Crucial Test of Faith” (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - “Disobedient Sons” through “Elijah” (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - “Enduement with Power” through “Every Christian, a Builder” (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - “The Excellency of Divine Law” through “An Expression of Love” (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - “Failure to Enter” through “The Folly of Worrying” (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - “The Forgiveness of Sin” through “Four Commands” (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - “Frances E. Willard” through “Friends and Friendships” (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - “Gain Through Loss” through “Glorifying in the Cross” (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - “God’s Call to Men” through “A Good Man” (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - “A Gracious Invitation” through “Growth in Grace” (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - “The Half Was Not Told” through “How to Find One’s Life Work?” (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - “Imitating Christ” through “Independence Sky” (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - “An Inspiring Reason for Loving God” through “Isaac” (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - “Jacob” through “Jesus Visits and Cleanses the Temple” (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - “Joseph” through “Judas Iscariot” (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - “The King’s Business” through “A Known God” (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - “Learning to Pray” through “Love: Its Basis and Results” (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - “Magnetism of the Cross” through “Mission of the Holy Spirit” (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - “Moral Decline: Its Cause and its Cure” through “My Church” (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Sermons—Typescripts
  - “Necessity of Pardon” through “Not Our Own” (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - “Occupy till I Come?” through “The Overcomer” (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - “Paul at Athens” through “The Phillipian Letter: Rules for Christian Unity” (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “The Practice and Power of Prayer” through “Purpose and Function of the Christian Church” (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - “The Reality and Value of the Unseen” through “The Resurrection Message” (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - “Retrospection, Introspection, and Prospection” through “The Reward of Fidelity” (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “Reward for Christian Service Certain” through “Ruth’s Choice” (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - “Sabbath Observance” through “Saul’s Rejections” (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - “Secret Friends of Jesus” through “The Shekinah” (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - “Sin” through “Some Hindrances to Worship” (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - “Some Objects of Prayer” through “The Stewardship of Time” (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - “Strength for the Day” through “A Supreme Desire” (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - “Taking Possession” through “The Throne of Grace” (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - “Tongues” through “Two Theories Tested By Scriptural Teaching” (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “Unconsciously Walking with Christ” through “Unthankfulness” (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - “Value of Concerted Action” through “Vows” (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - “A Warning Example” through “What Think Ye of Christ” (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - “What We Believe” through “Witness of the Spirit” (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - “The Young Ruler” through “Zeal” (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Manuscripts
  - “Conditions of Entering the Kingdom” (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1900 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1901 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1902 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1903 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1904 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1904 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1905 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - No Date (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - No Date (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Memorabilia
  - Writing Tablets (Box 3, Folder 11)